<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[All Your Base Are Belong To Me]]></title>
  <link href="http://aybabt.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aybabt.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-12T02:18:59-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://aybabt.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Antoine Grondin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Trick To Enhance Security Using Google Chrome]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2013/01/12/simple-trick-to-enhance-security-using-google-chrome/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-12T01:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2013/01/12/simple-trick-to-enhance-security-using-google-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With <a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/technology/technolog/us-warns-java-software-security-concerns-escalate-1B7938755">recent news</a> about exploits in Java web-browser plugins and recommendation to <a href="http://thenextweb.com/apps/2013/01/11/following-active-exploits-mozilla-adds-all-recent-versions-of-java-to-its-firefox-add-on-blocklist/">disable such plugins</a>, here&#8217;s a very simple trick that will protect you from most simple attacks that can be carried from websites.</p>

<iframe width="960" 
        height="720" 
        src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3vCAqq1lumw" 
        frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>
</iframe>


<p>Of course that&#8217;s not nearly enough to secure your computers, but it will surely help by greatly reducing the surface area on which your computer is vulnerable to threats.</p>

<h2>Along with that, common practices are:</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Not to run unknown executables.</strong></li>
<li>Especially <strong>not to run unknown executables with root/administrator privileges</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Not to use pirated software</strong>.</li>
<li>If you want to <strong>go on shaddy websites, use a virtual machine</strong>.</li>
<li>If you want to <strong>use pirated software, assume your computer is pirated/infected</strong> and any password, card number, account number you type - any key you press - is being recorded. Only use this computer to use those pirated software, use a physicaly different machine to do your banking/read your emails, login to any website.</li>
</ul>


<p>The use of pirated software could be a whole blog post in itself.  Simply put, just figure that inserting instructions of their choice into your lovely pirated game is trivial to crackers producing warez.  Hey, they need to pay their bills too!  Turning your computer to a botnet is an effective way to do so!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CUSEC - But I'm First Year!]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2013/01/09/cusec-but-im-first-year/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T12:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2013/01/09/cusec-but-im-first-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some people came to me wondering about the pertinence of <a href="http://2013.cusec.net/">CUSEC</a> for them: they&#8217;re first year, they don&#8217;t feel they have anything to sell to recruiters, they don&#8217;t have much confidence in their skills.</p>

<blockquote><p>Is it worth it for me to attend CUSEC?  I&#8217;m first year, I&#8217;ll never get a job!</p></blockquote>

<p>If you&#8217;re in that situation: CUSEC is just what you need.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>CUSEC is much more than a career fair.  The career fair is actually just a part of the conference, the main focus being on the keynotes, the talks, the workshops and the group activities. If you have to expect something from CUSEC, it should be that your brain will be filled by awesome stuff delivered to you by top notch speakers.</p>

<p>If you don&#8217;t feel confident in your skill, you don&#8217;t really have a feel of what&#8217;s this industry is all about, what&#8217;s the job(s) like, how to be relevant and employable: CUSEC is exactly the spark that will lead you to an understanding of what&#8217;s going on.  You might be wandering on campus, walking from classes to classes and thinking.</p>

<blockquote><p>That&#8217;s all great stuff, but where is this soft. eng./comp. sci. course going, what&#8217;s its purpose in my career dreams?</p></blockquote>

<p>CUSEC will be that window onto your future.  Now, I&#8217;m not going to pretend I know better than anyone else, because I don&#8217;t.  I&#8217;m second year, I&#8217;ll have my first COOP term this Summer (Amazon-look-at-me-I&#8217;m-coming!!!), I&#8217;m a super big newb in this.  But I feel I know a bit more than I did last year, I have a feeling of where I&#8217;m going and how to play my cards. So, here&#8217;s my little testimony about why CUSEC is relevant to first years, very much so.</p>

<h2>Last year, I was first year and it was my first time at CUSEC.</h2>

<p>When I first heard about CUSEC, it was on an email I received in November.  Before that I saw posters about the conference, but I&#8217;m not the kind of guy who pays attention to posters.  But anyway, when I received this e-mail, I was in a mood of &#8216;doing stuff&#8217;.  So, wondering if I should spend the money, I thought to myself</p>

<blockquote><p>What do I have to lose going?  Nothing (but a couple of $)</p></blockquote>

<p>And so I went.  And it was awesome.  But I was first year, I didn&#8217;t know shit, like nothing at all.  Once there, I realized there was a career fair going on all conference long.  I don&#8217;t know why but I never paid attention to the HD&#8217;s message regarding the career fairs - my attention span sucks like that. So I was there, in front of all those recruiters in front of impressive, big names and I remember feeling overwhelmed.</p>

<p>I went up the stairs of the hotel and thrown out a resume in 30 minutes.  Then I went downstair back to the conference floor and started to distribute my resume. God I had no clue what anything was about.  I went to the <a href="http://www.riotgames.com/">Riot Games booth</a> (makers of League of Legend), the guy there asking me</p>

<blockquote><p>So do you prefer &#8216;front end&#8217; of &#8216;back end&#8217; development?</p></blockquote>

<p>Say what? Dude, I can do &#8216;Hello World&#8217; in Java if you want, but I don&#8217;t understand your Alien Language!</p>

<p>By the end of the conference, I was exposed to a lot of Alien Language!  Awesome, mind blowing keynotes such at <a href="http://vimeo.com/36579366">Inventing on Principle</a> by <a href="http://www.worrydream.com">Bret Victor</a> (incredible talk that created waves around the world - notably inspiring a <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ibdknox/light-table">Kickstarter</a> by <a href="http://www.chris-granger.com/">Chris Granger</a>), tech talks by Dropbox, Coffeescript&#8217;s creator, Bioware, etc.  Lot of food for my thought.</p>

<p>The first step in understanding a domain is often to get a vocabulary for it.  Once you get the vocabulary, you know what to look for.  You have a name for things.  You can go on Google and find ressources to learn more.  CUSEC gave me an opportunity to see what&#8217;s going on, what&#8217;s the game</p>

<p>The second step in understanding a domain might as well be to get a feel for its community.  Knowing the kind of people forming it, the problems they deal with, the kind of work they do.  See their face, know their name, get them to know you, perhaps, a little bit?  Meet people working in the field you study for.  Learn what they have to say.  There&#8217;s a lot to gain from that exposure. Hell, you might just meet somebody who&#8217;ll remember you (!!) when they are looking to hire an intern!</p>

<p>So what should you do?  Last year, I went there and thought of my &#8216;CUSEC performance&#8217; in a <em>this-is-a-practice-shot</em> way.  I went to get a feel of what&#8217;s the recruiting game about, who are the people forming this industry.  My mission statement was</p>

<blockquote><p>Try to suceed,  and be ready for failure.</p></blockquote>

<p>Failure because, of course, the Riot Games recruiter was not very impressed that I had no clue about any of the words that got out of his mouth.  But it doesn&#8217;t matter, I got a glimpse at his Alien Language and this year, I can come back and try to speak it.  I&#8217;ll have a much better shot at it now that I know his secret codes and magical incantations.</p>

<p>Like anything, see it as an iterative process.  I go this year and I try to succeed, although the chance are low I&#8217;ll get a job. But whatever, next year my chance will be much better!  If you don&#8217;t start this year, in first year, you&#8217;ll be a year late in your 4-year-learning-opportunity.</p>

<p>Going to CUSEC in first year is the best thing you can do.  You&#8217;ll get tons of leads about the domain.  You&#8217;ll meet awesome people, make friends with people who care, you&#8217;ll have a blast with the keynotes, you&#8217;ll be inspired by the speakers, you&#8217;ll have a shot at the ways for your future.</p>

<p>So what do you have to lose going?  Please don&#8217;t have an attitude in the <strong>&#8216;is it worth trying&#8217;</strong> style, it leads to nothing.  The only thing preventing you from <em>doing</em> stuff is <em>you</em>, when you decide <em>not to do them</em>.  So go to CUSEC, see what happens!  Maybe you&#8217;ll hate it, maybe you&#8217;ll love it: at least you&#8217;ll know.</p>

<p>Like Edison said</p>

<blockquote><p>I have not failed. I&#8217;ve just found 10,000 ways that won&#8217;t work.</p></blockquote>

<p>So yeah. Go to CUSEC, it&#8217;s worth it, even if you don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ll land a job.  There&#8217;s so much more than that about CUSEC!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death of a Sandal]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2013/01/01/death-of-a-sandal/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T17:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2013/01/01/death-of-a-sandal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My right Sandal is dead.  I don&#8217;t know what killed it, and I&#8217;m not in a
mood to find the culprit. There&#8217;s no need for witch hunts, I&#8217;m better
than that, better than those who killed my right Sandal.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://aybabt.me/images/death_of_sandal.jpg" title="A broken sandal." alt="The Dead Sandal"></p>

<p>This Sandal walked in the sand of Dubai, in the dust of Kandahar, on the
roads of Queensland, Australia, on the beach of Paphos, Cyprus, on the
dirt of Sai Gon&#8217;s roads.  It has
visited the airports of Newark, Chicago, Ottawa, Vancouver, Brisbane,
Tokyo, Hong Kong, Singapore, Montreal, Doha, London and many
others.</p>

<p>This Sandal sustained my foot for thousands of kilometers.</p>

<p>Today, this sandal is no more.</p>

<p>The Sandal is dead.  Long live the Sandal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Survive Gnome Windowgeddon]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/24/gnome-puts-windows-out-of-screen-how-to-survive-windowgeddon/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-24T09:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/24/gnome-puts-windows-out-of-screen-how-to-survive-windowgeddon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You use Gnome 3. You usually have two monitors.  Today, you removed one
(for whatever reason).  You open applications and they are all
offscreen.  You curse, you cry, you think of the worst.  You contemplate
putting an end to your eternal agony.</p>

<p>Fear no more.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Multi-monitor support on Linux generally sucks.  Gnome 3 has many
flaws, people love to bash on it&#8230; but personnaly, I think it&#8217;s getting
better and better.  However, multi-monitor support sucks.</p>

<p>So how can you take that stupid out-of-screen window and put it back
into the Visible World ?</p>

<p><code>Alt-Tab</code> into the off-screen app, then <code>Alt-Space</code> it&#8217;s window&#8217;s menu
out of the darkness.  Press <code>m</code> to free it from its constraints and
<code>wiggle-your-mouse-on-the-screen</code> the app back into a more decent
position.</p>

<p>You just saved the day.  Carry on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MyClass Naming Pattern Considered Evil]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/22/myclass-naming-pattern-considered-evil/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T05:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/22/myclass-naming-pattern-considered-evil</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From time to time, I&#8217;ve seen people online or at school having a class
such as:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">Shredder</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kt">void</span> <span class="nf">shredEverything</span><span class="o">(){</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="c1">// destroyyyyyy</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>and rolling out custom implementation using this kind of brain-farted
naming pattern:<!-- more --></p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">MyShredder</span> <span class="kd">extends</span> <span class="n">Shredder</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nd">@Override</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kt">void</span> <span class="nf">shredEverything</span><span class="o">(){</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="c1">// oh hai, I just want to shred paper, nothing else</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Huuuuuuuurrrrrrr&#8230;..</p>

<p>You know what?  JUST NAME YOUR CLASS <code>PaperShredder</code> and LET US ALL BE
HAPPIER!</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">PaperShredder</span> <span class="kd">extends</span> <span class="n">Shredder</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="cm">/** This thing only shreds paper */</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>When I eventually come across a stack trace with the <code>MyImplementation</code>
name that your brain farted, I&#8217;m left to wonder what kind of information you
expect readers to grasp from that particular name.</p>

<p>I understand that you&#8217;re proud of your code, that you think &#8220;Hey guys,
  that&#8217;s MY class!&#8221; and everything, but knowing that this is
  <code>YourImplementation</code> is pretty fucking pointless to everybody.</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&#8217;t name your classes with the <code>My</code> prefix!!!</p></blockquote>

<p>Just don&#8217;t do it!  If you implement something at random and feel there&#8217;s
no better name coming to your mind at that time, well&#8230; just rename it
anyway!</p>

<p>There&#8217;s no way on earth that <code>MyException</code> will ever mean something
useful to anybody, not even you.  If you don&#8217;t understand that, please
hand over your keyboard to your kindergarten instructor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Get A Free Ride And A Pizza]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/12/how-to-get-a-free-ride-and-a-pizza/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T20:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/12/how-to-get-a-free-ride-and-a-pizza</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was young, I didn&#8217;t have a car, I worked in a gaz station and it was
Winter.  The last bus coming in my part of town had passed its last run
an hour ago, I was hungry and cold.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So I walked to the closest pizzeria.  I called them and ordered a pizza
to be delivered to my house.</p>

<p>Then I went to the back entrance and asked the delivery guys if they
would accept to deliver me with my pizza, given that I would give them a
decent tip.</p>

<p>So for the price of a pizza and the subsequent tip I would have paid
anyway to the delivery guy, I also got a ride home.  The same ride would
have cost me 15$ of taxi, back then.</p>

<p>So yeah. Hacking life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[uOttawa at CUSEC in Numbers]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/10/uottawa-at-cusec-in-numbers/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-10T22:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/10/uottawa-at-cusec-in-numbers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello people.</p>

<p>As you may know, I&#8217;m Antoine Grondin and I&#8217;m taking care of bringing a
bunch of people to CUSEC this year.  As you may also know, today was the
last day to get your ticket and be eligible for up to 100%
reimbursement.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you didn&#8217;t get your ticket at this time, fear no more.  I&#8217;ll try to
get more funding this Winter (I applied for the Fall&#8217;s funding round,
I&#8217;ll apply again for the Winter round).</p>

<p>In the mean time, here are some numbers about our delegation, as it is
right NOW (the graphs are interactive, so they&#8217;ll update as we go
forward in the time continuum - or are we going <em>forward</em>?? dun dun
dun).</p>

<blockquote><p>GRAPHS !!!1!!ONE</p></blockquote>

<p>Whoooo, before I let you loose with the graphs, a few updates:</p>

<ul>
<li>We broke the 39 limit!  DON&#8217;T WORRY! I&#8217;ll apply for funding again this
Winter (I&#8217;m repeating myself). Also, I&#8217;ll confirm the numbers tomorrow
when I get to catch everybody&#8217;s registration sheet at the IEEE office.</li>
<li>This will be the biggest delegation uOttawa sent to CUSEC.  At least
as far as I&#8217;ve managed to count back.</li>
<li>We&#8217;re (at the time of writing) way ahead of Waterloo (2nd), and way ahead of
all the other Universities as well. Whatever it might be worth!</li>
<li>Get your résumé ready for CUSEC!  You should look up the sponsors at
<a href="http://2013.cusec.net/">CUSEC.net</a> and look up their &#8220;Career&#8221; or &#8220;Job&#8221; page.  You&#8217;ll find what kind of
jobs/internships they offer, and you won&#8217;t look like a moron when you
get to their booth with your résumé.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&#8217;ll try to elaborate more on the résumé thing before we get off.</p>

<h2>A pie made of engineering students, and one random physics/math dude</h2>

<p>This is pretty straight forward, how many people from each program are
coming:</p>

<script type="text/javascript" src="http://aybabt.me//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/static/modules/gviz/1.0/chart.js"> {"dataSourceUrl":"//docs.google.com/spreadsheet/tq?key=0Av3wmrjnD3V3dDlsRWQ1TFN6RXp0dGxLcl80MDVVRWc&transpose=0&headers=1&range=G2%3AH7&gid=2&pub=1","options":{"titleTextStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#000","fontSize":16},"animation":{"duration":500},"colors":["#3366CC","#DC3912","#FF9900","#109618","#990099","#0099C6","#DD4477","#66AA00","#B82E2E","#316395","#994499","#22AA99","#AAAA11","#6633CC","#E67300","#8B0707","#651067","#329262","#5574A6","#3B3EAC","#B77322","#16D620","#B91383","#F4359E","#9C5935","#A9C413","#2A778D","#668D1C","#BEA413","#0C5922","#743411"],"width":551,"is3D":true,"hAxis":{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},"vAxes":[{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null}],"pieHole":0,"booleanRole":"certainty","title":"Programs","height":490,"legend":"bottom","tooltip":{}},"state":{},"view":{},"chartType":"PieChart","chartName":"Chart 2"} </script>


<h2>A pie made of diversityyyy</h2>

<p>Please note that our delegation is, as far as I know, the one that has the
greatest ratio of female/male.  This is pretty good.</p>

<script type="text/javascript" src="http://aybabt.me//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/static/modules/gviz/1.0/chart.js"> {"dataSourceUrl":"//docs.google.com/spreadsheet/tq?key=0Av3wmrjnD3V3dDlsRWQ1TFN6RXp0dGxLcl80MDVVRWc&transpose=0&headers=0&range=D3%3AE4&gid=2&pub=1","options":{"titleTextStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#000","fontSize":16},"animation":{"duration":500},"colors":["#3366cc","#dc3912","#FF9900","#109618","#990099","#0099C6","#DD4477","#66AA00","#B82E2E","#316395","#994499","#22AA99","#AAAA11","#6633CC","#E67300","#8B0707","#651067","#329262","#5574A6","#3B3EAC","#B77322","#16D620","#B91383","#F4359E","#9C5935","#A9C413","#2A778D","#668D1C","#BEA413","#0C5922","#743411"],"width":502,"is3D":true,"hAxis":{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},"vAxes":[{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null}],"pieHole":0,"title":"Gender proportion","booleanRole":"certainty","height":483,"legend":"bottom","tooltip":{}},"state":{},"view":{},"chartType":"PieChart","chartName":"Chart 1"} </script>


<h2>A timeline of the registrations</h2>

<p>We can see that student have an incontrollable tendency to get
registrated in exponential manner.</p>

<p>We could say something like:</p>

<ul>
<li>A first person is registered (1)</li>
<li>This person convinced another student (2)</li>
<li>Who convinced two other students (4)</li>
<li>&#8230;</li>
<li>Etc, everybody convinces at least one other person, and then we grow as
2<sup>n.</sup></li>
</ul>


<p>But the truth is most likely that we&#8217;re all lazy, greedy and didn&#8217;t want
to put the money in until the very last few days.</p>

<script type="text/javascript" src="http://aybabt.me//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/static/modules/gviz/1.0/chart.js"> {"dataSourceUrl":"//docs.google.com/spreadsheet/tq?key=0Av3wmrjnD3V3dDlsRWQ1TFN6RXp0dGxLcl80MDVVRWc&transpose=0&headers=0&range=A1%3AB101&gid=2&pub=1","options":{"displayAnnotations":true,"titleTextStyle":{"fontSize":16},"vAxes":[{"useFormatFromData":true,"title":"Left vertical axis title","minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null}],"booleanRole":"certainty","title":"Chart title","wmode":"opaque","hAxis":{"useFormatFromData":true,"title":"Horizontal axis title","minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},"width":600,"height":371},"state":{},"view":{},"chartType":"AnnotatedTimeLine","chartName":"Chart 4"} </script>


<h3>T-shirtssss</h3>

<p>There&#8217;s no point to this chart.</p>

<script type="text/javascript" src="http://aybabt.me//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/static/modules/gviz/1.0/chart.js"> {"dataSourceUrl":"//docs.google.com/spreadsheet/tq?key=0Av3wmrjnD3V3dDlsRWQ1TFN6RXp0dGxLcl80MDVVRWc&transpose=0&headers=0&range=D10%3AE13&gid=2&pub=1","options":{"titleTextStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#000","fontSize":16},"animation":{"duration":500},"colors":["#3366CC","#DC3912","#FF9900","#109618","#990099","#0099C6","#DD4477","#66AA00","#B82E2E","#316395","#994499","#22AA99","#AAAA11","#6633CC","#E67300","#8B0707","#651067","#329262","#5574A6","#3B3EAC","#B77322","#16D620","#B91383","#F4359E","#9C5935","#A9C413","#2A778D","#668D1C","#BEA413","#0C5922","#743411"],"width":509,"is3D":true,"hAxis":{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},"vAxes":[{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null},{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null}],"pieHole":0,"booleanRole":"certainty","title":"T-Shirt sizes lol","height":500,"legend":"bottom","tooltip":{}},"state":{},"view":{},"chartType":"PieChart","chartName":"Chart 3"} </script>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping an Heroku instance alive]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/04/keeping-an-heroku-instance-alive/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T20:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/04/keeping-an-heroku-instance-alive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to have a Linode VM.  I still have a Linode VM.  But I regularly
fuck up my setup (lock myself out, get lost in between nginx and
apache&#8217;s install and config files, mess up my iptables rules, etc), so
it&#8217;s not the best platform to use when I want to explore stuff about
web development.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Heroku is great for that, you can get your instance for free and the
deployment is a breeze.  But your free instance (or dyno) is turned off
after every hour of inactivity on your website.  This is quite annoying.
It means the visitor coming an hour after the last visitor will see the
page load for a dozen of seconds before being served anything, while heroku
turns your dyno back online.</p>

<p>So here&#8217;s a pretty trivial solution to this annoyance:</p>

<blockquote><p>CRON JOBS!</p></blockquote>

<p>Yayyyyy!  Create a small script that gets a pages from your app every
hour, and put that in your crontab jobs!  Too simple!</p>

<p>So I did this little script:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>heroku-keep-alive</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="c1">#!/usr/bin/env ruby</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">require</span> <span class="s1">&#39;net/http&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">APPS</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s2">&quot;aybabtme&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">get_app_uri</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="n">app_name</span> <span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">heroku_app</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;http://</span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">app_name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">.heroku.com/index.html&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="no">URI</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">parse</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">heroku_app</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">wake_up_instance_at_uri</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="n">uri</span> <span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">res</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Net</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">HTTP</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">get_response</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">uri</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">res</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">code</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s2">&quot;301&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">res</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Net</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">HTTP</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">get_response</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="no">URI</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">parse</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">res</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">header</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;location&#39;</span><span class="o">]</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">APPS</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">each</span> <span class="k">do</span> <span class="o">|</span><span class="n">app_name</span><span class="o">|</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">uri</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">get_app_uri</span> <span class="n">app_name</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">wake_up_instance_at_uri</span> <span class="n">uri</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Just fill in your app names in the <code>APPS</code> array, save it somewhere and</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>chmod +x /path/to/heroku-keep-alive
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>crontab  <span class="c"># will overwrite any previous jobs</span>
</span><span class='line'>0 * * * * /path/to/heroku-keep-alive
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Press <code>Ctrl+D</code>. Confirm it&#8217;s been added to your cron jobs:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>crontab -l
</span><span class='line'>0 * * * * /path/to/heroku-keep-alive
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Yayyy, victory! I&#8217;ve, ironically, put this cron job on my Linode,
since it&#8217;s always turned on.  You could put that on your *nix box
 at home, given that it should be turned on most of the time.</p>

<p>Actually, all you really need is to <code>wget</code> your index (<code>curl</code> won&#8217;t do
it, heroku has a permanent redirect to your instance and <code>curl</code> won&#8217;t
follow it), but that would be <em>too</em> simple. Hey, where&#8217;s the fun if
there&#8217;s no code at all?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A bright new world]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/03/a-bright-new-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-03T20:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/03/a-bright-new-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog is now alive, powered by Octopress.  Watch out!  It may one
day overpower its creator and try to destroy humanity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
