<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: code | All Your Base Are Belong To Me]]></title>
  <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/categories/code/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aybabt.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-10T00:48:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://aybabt.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Antoine Grondin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MyClass Naming Pattern Considered Evil]]></title>
    <link href="http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/22/myclass-naming-pattern-considered-evil/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T05:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://aybabt.me/blog/2012/12/22/myclass-naming-pattern-considered-evil</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From time to time, I've seen people online or at school having a class
such as:</p>

<p>``` java
public class Shredder {</p>

<pre><code>public void shredEverything(){
  // destroyyyyyy
}
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>and rolling out custom implementation using this kind of brain-farted
naming pattern:<!-- more -->
``` java
public class MyShredder extends Shredder {</p>

<pre><code>@Override
public void shredEverything(){
  // oh hai, I just want to shred paper, nothing else
}
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>Huuuuuuuurrrrrrr.....</p>

<p>You know what?  JUST NAME YOUR CLASS <code>PaperShredder</code> and LET US ALL BE
HAPPIER!</p>

<p>``` java
public class PaperShredder extends Shredder {</p>

<pre><code>/** This thing only shreds paper */
</code></pre>

<p>}
```</p>

<p>When I eventually come across a stack trace with the <code>MyImplementation</code>
name that your brain farted, I'm left to wonder what kind of information you
expect readers to grasp from that particular name.</p>

<p>I understand that you're proud of your code, that you think "Hey guys,
  that's MY class!" and everything, but knowing that this is
  <code>YourImplementation</code> is pretty fucking pointless to everybody.</p>

<blockquote><p>Don't name your classes with the <code>My</code> prefix!!!</p></blockquote>

<p>Just don't do it!  If you implement something at random and feel there's
no better name coming to your mind at that time, well... just rename it
anyway!</p>

<p>There's no way on earth that <code>MyException</code> will ever mean something
useful to anybody, not even you.  If you don't understand that, please
hand over your keyboard to your kindergarten instructor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
